Guide to the Jane Howard Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Correspondence
  - Subseries VII.4: Arranged (Family)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1961 - 1983 (Box 69)
    - The Howard Family Miscellaneous correspondence, 1961 - 1983 (Box 70)
      [Includes many letters from R.P. Howard to Jane Howard; correspondence from the Condon Family; sympathy correspondence regarding the death of R. P. Howard.]
- Series VIII: Writings
  - Subseries VIII.1: Margaret Mead: A Life
    Research materials, Boxes 71 - 77, Boxes 71 - 74 are arranged alphabetically by individuals' last names.
    - A - E (Box 71)
      [Includes correspondence, research materials, notes.]
    - F - H (Box 72)
    - H - R (Box 73)
    - R - Z (Box 74)
      [Includes correspondence, research materials, notes, and one folder of misc. items.]
    - Miscellaneous research materials (Box 75)
      [Includes notes and drafts.]
    - Miscellaneous research materials (Box 76)
      [Includes notes and post-publication materials.]
    - Printed material from research files. (Box 77)
      [Includes books, booklets, clippings, pamphlets, brochures and misc.]
  - Subseries VIII.2: Families
    - Research and related materials (Box 78)
      [Includes notes, fragmentary drafts, promotional and touring materials and book reviews. Some material may also refer to A Different Woman.]
  - Subseries VIII.3: Please Touch
    - Research and related materials (Box 79)
      [Includes notes, fragmentary drafts, promotional and touring materials, clippings and book reviews.]
  - Subseries VIII.4: A Different Woman
    - Research and related materials (Box 80)
      [Includes printed matter, notes, drafts, promotional and touring materials, clippings and book reviews. Some material may also refer to Families.]
  - Subseries VIII.5: Lost In The Interior, a work in progress
    Boxes 81 - 86
    - Research and related materials (Box 81)
      [Includes research materials, printed matter, clippings, notes and general correspondence.]
    - Research and related materials (Box 82)
      [Includes research materials, printed matter, clippings, notes, a list of travels and author's bibliographies.]
    - Research and related materials (Box 83)
      [Includes research materials, topical research, printed matter, clippings, notes, xeroxed articles and book exerpts.]
    - Chapter drafts and notes (Box 84)
      [Includes mostly typed drafts with handwritten edits.]
    - Chapter drafts and notes (Box 85)
      [Includes mostly typed drafts with handwritten edits, fragments of drafts, structure notes, interveiw notes, travel journal fragments, Hoard Family reunion materials and various research materials.]
    - Printed materials from research files (Box 86)
      [Includes pamphlets, booklets, brochures, maps, directories, newsletters, magazines, and other miscellaneous items.]
  - Subseries VIII.6: Unpublished Manuscript
    Boxes 87 - 88, most likely derived from research for the Lost in the Interior project.
    - Parts I, II and III, edited and unedited typescript drafts (Box 87)
      [As their subject matter is the Midwest, it is likely that these unpublished manuscripts are the result of the research and writing that Howard placed under the heading Lost in the Interior.]
    - Parts IV a and IV b, typescript drafts (Box 88)
      [Box also inclues notes, research and progress reports.]
  - Subseries VIII.7: Life Magazine
    - Research materials, notes and drafts (Box 89)
      [Includes an index of published articles, clippings, notebooks, interview notes and various related items.]
  - Subseries VIII.8: Lear's Magazine
    Boxes 90 - 97, "A Woman for Lear's" column. Boxes 90 - 92: pieces published in the column. Boxes 93 - 97: unpublished pieces, drafts, nominations or research on candidates.
    - Research materials and drafts, January 1990 - October 1990 (Box 90)
      [Includes various background materials on subjects, interviews, notes and revisions, proofs and related correspondence.]
    - Research materials and drafts, November 1990 - August 1991 (Box 91)
    - Research materials and drafts, September - October 1991 (Box 92)
      [Includes instructions for finding candidates, master lists of candidates from 1989 - 1992, various background materials on subjects, interviews, notes and revisions, proofs and related correspondence.]
    - Candidates A - D (Box 93)
      [Includes research and background materials regarding candidates and related correspondence.]
    - Candidates E - L (Box 94)
    - Candidates M - S (Box 95)
    - Candidates S, T - Z (Box 96)
    - Candidates and nominees for column (Box 97)
      [Includes research and background materials regarding candidates and nominees, drafts, notes, rejected candiates and drafts and misc. ]
  - Subseries VIII.9: Freelance Writings
    Boxes 98 - 102
    - 50 Plus - Family Circle (Box 98)
      [Includes research materials, drafts, notes, clips, interview materials, galleys.]
    - Family Weekly - Madamoiselle (Box 99)
      [Includes research materials, drafts, notes, clips, interview materials and book review materials.]
    - More - People (Box 100)
      [Includes research materials, drafts, notes, clips and interview materials.]
    - Washington Post - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 101)
      [Includes research and book review materials, drafts, notes, lists of published freelance articles, loose clips and a yellow binder of clips.]
    - Playboy - Vogue (Box 102)
      [Includes research and interview materials, drafts, notes, clips and galleys.]
  - Subseries VIII.10: Miscellaneous Writings
    Boxes 103 - 104
    - By Jane Howard, drafts and notes (Box 103)
      [Includes interview notes and drafts, autobiographical writings,a spiral notebook and research materials. Some fragments are undated, unidentified or possibly unpublished.]
    - By other people, drafts and notes (Box 104)
      [Includes partial manuscripts and drafts -- some with comments by Jane Howard --, an interview with Howard, and a signed MFA thesis by Jane Smiley.]
  - Subseries VIII.11: Speeches
    - Drafts, notes and related correspondence (Box 105)
      [Includes materials from Jane Howard's speeches regarding various publications, speeches given at colleges and universities, miscellaneous speaking engagements and correspondence regarding speaking requests.]
- Series IX: Teaching Materials
  Boxes 106 - 109
  - Subseries IX.1: Columbia University
    - Lecture notes, readings, handouts, student work and other related materials (Box 106)
  - Subseries IX.2: Split Rock Arts Program and Student Work
    - Lecture notes, readings, handouts, class materials, student work and other related materials (Box 107)
      [Includes evaluations, reading list, stories by students, Split Rock catalog.]
  - Subseries IX.3: University of Iowa, Univeristy of Georgia, Yale, S.U.N.Y.at Albany
    - Lecture notes, readings, class materials and excercises, student work, correspondence and other related materials (Box 108)
      [Includes "Advice on Teaching Writing," reading lists, "Exemplary Prose," "What Teaching's Taught Me," and examples of the use of humor in writing.]
  - Subseries IX.4: Miscellaneous Teaching Materials
    - Lecture notes, readings, class materials and excercises, student work, correspondence, faculty reports, bulletins and other related materials (Box 109)
      [ Includes materials regarding biographical writing, many of materials are from the Columbia Writing Division.]
- Series X: Datebooks and Calendars
  - , 1961 - 1977, (20 volumes, 8 folders folder) (Box 110)
- Series XI: Journals
  Boxes 111-129
  - Volumes 1 - 10, notebooks and loose pages in folders, 1956 - 1971 (Box 111)
  - Volumes 11 - 15, loose pages in folders, 1973 - 74 (Box 112)
    [some parts fragmentary]
  - Volumes 16 - 22, loose pages in folders and notebooks, 1975 - 1979 (Box 113)
  - Volumes 23 - 32, 1970 - 1980, (10 notebooks handwritten) (Box 114)
  - Volumes 33 - 45, May 1980 - April 1981, (13 notebooks handwritten) (Box 115)
  - Volumes 46 - 58, May 1981 - July 1982, (13 notebooks handwritten) (Box 116)
  - Volumes 59 - 71, July 1982 - June 1983, (13 notebooks handwritten) (Box 117)
  - Volumes 72 - 84, June 1983 - April 1984, (13 notebooks handwritten) (Box 118)
  - Volumes 85 - 97, 29 April, 1984 - 10 March, 1985, (13 notebooks handwritten) (Box 119)
  - Volumes 98 - 109, 11 March, 1985 - 27 November, 1985, (12 notebooks handwritten) (Box 120)
  - Volumes 110 - 121, December 1985 - November 1986, (12 notebooks handwritten) (Box 121)
  - Volumes 122 - 133, 22 November 1986 - 28 October 1987, (12 notebooks handwritten) (Box 122)
  - Volumes 134 - 145, November 1987 - 30 October 1988, (12 notebooks handwritten) (Box 123)
  - Loose leaf journal entries, January 1987 - December 1988, (4 folders t.s.) (Box 124)
    [Entries transcribed from handwritten journals and edited. Some dates unclear.]
  - Volumes 146 - 157, October 1988 - October 1989, (12 notebooks handwritten) (Box 125)
  - Volumes 158 - 170, November 1989 - March 1991, (13 notebooks handwritten) (Box 126)
  - Volumes 171 - 182, April 1991 - June 1992, (12 notebooks handwritten) (Box 127)
  - Volumes 183 - 194, June 1992 - December 1993, (12 notebooks handwritten) (Box 128)
  - Volumes 195 - 204, December 1993 - January 1996, (10 notebooks handwritten) (Box 129)
- Series XII: Memorabilia
  Boxes 130 - 132
  - Subseries XII.1: School Years
    - Miscellaneous school and school-related items from elementary school through college. (Box 130)
      [Includes a yearbook, school papers, pieces written for school publications.]
  - Subseries XII.2: Howard Family
    - Miscellaneous personal items, keepsakes and items of family business (Box 131)
      [Includes childhood drawings, writings by Robert P. Howard, address lists, home inventories, genealogical information, and items regarding various family members' deaths, marriages, retirement, military service.]
  - Subseries XII.3: Diplomas and Awards
    - Academic diplomas and award certificates, framed and unframed (Box 132)
      [Chicago Foundation for Literature Award, New Trier High School, University of Michigan, Grinnell College, Hamline University.]
- Series XIII: Documents
  - Official documents regarding finances, legal affairs or contracts (Box 133)
- Series XIV: Printed Material
  - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 134)
    [Includes materials used in research, clippings and newsprint, dust jackets, and items from travel and speaking engagements or requests.]
- Series XV: Topical Files
  - Subseries XV.1: Art
    - Materials on woodworking (Box 135)
  - Subseries XV.2: Business
    - Related items (Box 135)
      [Clippings saved by Jane Howard]
  - Subseries XV.3: Didion/Dunne
    - Items from Jane Howard's personal communication with Joan Didion and John Dunne (Box 135)
      [Clippings and some handwritten notes]
  - Subseries XV.4: Health
    - Related items (Box 135)
  - Subseries XV.5: Lear's Magazine
    - Media coverage of Lear's magazine (Box 135)
  - Subseries XV.6: Howard, Jane
    - Various media and personal items concerning Jane Howard (Box 135)
      [Includes media coverage of J.H. and clippings, autobiographical notes, lists of published works, and a handwritten list of stories written]
  - Subseries XV.7: Literature
    - Related items (Box 135)
      [Includes information about and reviews of books, information about creative writing, and clippings about libraries.]
  - Subseries XV.8: Media
    - Related items (Box 135)
      [Includes items regarding television, radio, the press.]
  - Subseries XV.9: Music
    - Related items (Box 135)
      [Includes items regarding the Symphony of the United Nations and Joseph Eger.]
  - Subseries XV.10: People
    - Various items regarding individuals (Box 135)
  - Subseries XV.11: Politics
    - Related items (Box 135)
  - Subseries XV.12: Religion
    - Related items (Box 135)
      [Eastern and Western religions]
  - Subseries XV.13: Simon and Schuster
    - Various media items relating to the company Simon and Schuster (Box 135)
  - Subseries XV.14: Miscellaneous
    - Various items (Box 135)
- Seris XVI: Miscellaneous Files
  - Various items (Box 136)
    [Mostly personal items including lists, Howard's plan for arranging her personal papers, fragmentary writings and notes, unidentified writings, book ideas.]
- Seris XVII: Audiotapes
  - Various audiotapes, [n.d.] & ca. 1970-1989, (18 cassettes, 1 five-inch reel) (Box 137)
    [Many tapes relate to the Margaret Mead: A Life project.]
- Series XVIII: Scrapbooks
  Boxes 138 - 141
  - Subseries XVIII.1: Families and Miscellaneous Writings
    - Three folders of materials relating to the writing and research of Families; one green binder of various clippings of Howard's work. (Box 138)
      [Includes reviews, clippings, correspondence.]
  - Subseries XVIII.2: Please Touch and A Different Woman
    - One black binder of reviews and interviews relating to Please Touch; one yellow binder of reviews of A Different Woman. (Box 139)
  - Subseries XVIII.3: MacDowell Colony
    - One black binder containing photographs and information about the art program at the Colony; one folder of photographs and negatives that accompanied the scrapbook; one folder of materials related to the Colony and the surrounding region that also accompanied the scrapbook., New Hampshire (Box 140)
  - Subseries XVIII.4: Life Magazine
    - One red binder of clips of Howard's LIFE pieces; three folders of loose LIFE clippings by Howard arranged alphabetically by subject (or interviewee); one folder of miscellaneous loose LIFE clippings; one folder of various LIFE magazines. (Box 141)
      [Red binder also contains some photographs]
- Series XIX: Photographs
  Boxes 142 - 143
  - Subseries XIX.1: Life Magazine
    - One red binder of various photographs taken to accompany Howard's stories in LIFE. (Box 142)
  - Subseries XIX.2: Life Magazine and The Howard Family
    - Loose Life photographs arranged in folders alphabetically by subject; one folder of unidentified LIFE photos; one folder of Jane Howard's personal and family photos; one folder of negatives. (Box 143)
- Series XX: Addresses
  Alphabetically arranged cards in black metal box
  - Miscellaneous addresses and phone numbers, business and personal, 1979 - 1982 [?] (Box 144)